<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Android on all about apps</title>
    <link>https://code.allaboutapps.at/categories/android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Android on all about apps</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 10:30:11 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://code.allaboutapps.at/categories/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Pagination With Epoxy &amp; Datasources</title>
      <link>https://code.allaboutapps.at/articles/advanced-pagination-with-epoxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 10:30:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.allaboutapps.at/articles/advanced-pagination-with-epoxy/</guid>
      <description>Many developers still avoid using Epoxy. I even hesitated for a long time because of the boilerplate coming a long with epoxy and its models, but after reading this post at the latest, you may consider using epoxy, when paging is needed.
So in this post we gonna build pagination with the jetpack‘s paging library, and epoxy, which has an own controller for paging.
We gonna use reddit as our api, by simply adding .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TimingLogger</title>
      <link>https://code.allaboutapps.at/articles/timing-logger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 16:02:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.allaboutapps.at/articles/timing-logger/</guid>
      <description>TimingLogger Sometimes developers needs to analyze performance of a small friction of code. Maybe a RecyclerView is not scrolling smoothly or a calculation needs too much time, we have to split it up and try to find the line or block that runs inefficently. We all know to get a smooth user experience we only have 16ms for each frame to render. So it is very important to locate and optimize inefficient code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Template Project</title>
      <link>https://code.allaboutapps.at/articles/android-template-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 16:01:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.allaboutapps.at/articles/android-template-project/</guid>
      <description>Team Android Project Template As a software development company we are starting new projects every few weeks. With every project we create a jira ticket called Project Setup.
We walked through all our Project Setup Jira tickets and calculated the average hours for this kind of task: In average every android project needs about 3.5 hours for a simple setup. On the other hand the project setup is boring and no developer likes that work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>