<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lb on all about apps</title>
    <link>https://code.allaboutapps.at/authors/lb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lb on all about apps</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 09:57:26 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://code.allaboutapps.at/authors/lb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Proper Material Theming in a Multi-Module Setup</title>
      <link>https://code.allaboutapps.at/articles/material-theming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 09:57:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.allaboutapps.at/articles/material-theming/</guid>
      <description>Basic Setup Recently an opportunity opened up for us to fully utilize a Material Theming &amp;amp; Styling setup in one of our new projects. We took some time to dig into this topic and made a clean setup in order to prepare for a long-term running project. This article will describe the results and our learnings.
Let&#39;s start with the basic setup: as with all of our projects we use our A3AndroidTemplate as a starting point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Jetpack Navigation Pitfalls &amp; Tricks</title>
      <link>https://code.allaboutapps.at/articles/android-jetpack-navigation-pitfalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 10:03:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.allaboutapps.at/articles/android-jetpack-navigation-pitfalls/</guid>
      <description>Table of content  Send Args to fragments within activities Use startActivityForResult with the Navigation library Use generic naming for action names Reuse fragments in multiple navigation graphs TLDR Further readings  Navigation library from Jetpack offers a great variety of helpful tools, especially with the SafeArgs extension. My last project contained many different navigation flows paired with a large number of screens, so I decided to try the new navigation library which had just reached a stable release.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>